soundtrends.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy | Legal Information

The following advice on data protection applies when you visit our website https://www.native-instruments.com, including the use of the associated online shop. 

We are aware that you take the protection of your personal data very seriously, and the protection of your personal data is equally important to Native Instruments. For this reason, we strictly comply with statutory provisions when collecting, processing and using your data. We apply technical and organisational measures to ensure the protection of the personal data we receive from you. This includes training our employees in their obligation to comply with data privacy guidelines (customer services are exclusively implemented by Native Instruments Group employees), as well as procedural and digital security measures related to the processing of your data.

In the following section we will provide information about the methods, purpose and scope of the data processing which takes place when you visit our website and/or our online shop. 

We continuously strive to help you with any questions you may have regarding data processing issues relevant to our online services. If you have any questions, please contact the department responsible for data processing:

Native Instruments GmbH  
Data protection officer: Kai-Hendrik Weutzing  
Schlesische Str. 29-30  
10997 Berlin, Germany  
Email: privacy@native-instruments.de 

## 1\. Personal Data

The following information relates to the processing of your personal data. Personal data refers to all data which refers to you personally, i.e., name, address, email address, payment information or your activities as a user.

## 2\. Data Capture Every Time You Access the Website

 **a) Usage Data**

Every time you access the website, even if it is only to look for information and you do not log in or register a customer account, or otherwise deliberately transfer information (for example by signing up for a newsletter), we will capture the following data, transmitted by your browser, which allow you to visit the website (usage data): 

  * IP address
  * Date and time of the request
  * Duration of the visit to the website
  * Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT) 
  * Contents of request (actual page) 
  * Access status/HTTP-status code 
  * Respectively transmitted data quantities 
  * Which website the request is coming from 
  * Browser, browser language, browser software version
  * Operating system 

For IT security reasons, we will save your IP address in our IT system log files for 7 days following your website visit in order to recognize and prevent (Distributed) Denial of Service attacks. After the 7 days have passed your IP address will be anonymized by removing the last 8 bits.

If your IP address is saved in unabbreviated format, we will only aggregate it with any of the usage data mentioned above if we have a legitimate interest.

**b) Cookies**

When using our website as well as our online shop, cookies are saved on the device you use to access the page. They enable the Native Instruments systems to recognize your browser and to provide services which are of interest to you personally.

Cookies are small text files (alphanumeric identification symbols) which are stored on users’ end devices when they visit a website. When the same website is visited again, the information which was saved will then be sent back to the participating server. We use first-party cookies and third-party cookies, which can be designed as session cookies or temporary cookies. 

Session cookies are automatically deleted from your hard drive after your browser session. These cookies store a so-called session ID, which is assigned various requests from your browser during a shared session. This type of cookie is used in relation to the basket function in the online shop as well as to user and licence data. Its use is technically required in order to be able to connect your user account with your actions over separate visits.

Temporary cookies are deleted after a pre-determined amount of time. These cookies allow us to recognize a repeated website visit based on the feedback from the cookies to the participating server over various browser sessions, in order to – for example – maintain the selected language settings over various website visits. A connection to your user account (where applicable) and the possible identification will only be implemented if you select the “Remember me” function during login. In this way, we can provide a personalized shopping experience. 

Third-party cookies are only set by servers if they are not identical with our servers, i.e. if they come from other websites you have visited. In contrast, first-party cookies on browsers are not accessible across domains. Third-party cookies are used when using our website and our online shop by some third-party companies (for further details about some selected providers used by us, see below under c). 

By using these third-party cookies, also known as “tracking cookies”, a user’s visits to various websites can be assigned to the specific visitor. This allows us to draw conclusions about the visitor’s interests and to accordingly customize websites (personalization, for example through individually tailored advertisements). 

You also have the option of configuring your browser so that specific types of cookies are not allowed or deleted. You can also visit our website if your browser settings block the placing of cookies or if you do not agree with having cookies placed on your hard drive. We would like to inform you, however, that if you do so, you may not be able to fully use all features on our website, in particular purchases via the use of a virtual basket, which will not be possible for technical reasons (see above).

**c) Third-Party Providers**

**(aa) Google Analytics**

As a part of our internet presence we use Google Analytics, which is a web analysis tool provided by Google Inc. Google Analytics uses cookies to analyze how our website is used. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website, including the abbreviated IP address, is transferred to and stored on a Google server, in some cases located in the USA. The evaluation by Google is exclusively carried out in an anonymous process in which the code expansion provided by Google “anonymizeIp” deletes the last 8 bits of your IP address, therefore anonymizing it for subsequent data processing.

If you have registered a user account with us, we will additionally use a so-called "User ID" for this service. This is a unique, permanent and personalized symbol sequence which we assign to you when you first log in to your user account. When you visit the website and are logged in to your user account, the website activities are assigned to your permanent user ID. This ID is not assigned to a specific end device (smartphone, laptop, etc.), but to you personally. In conjunction with Google Universal Analytics, this User ID is transmitted to Google, where it is used by us at Google as a pseudonym for you as a user. The data accumulated by Google are therefore anonymized for Google, as the service does not have the option to create a link to your user account and therefore to your personal data.

Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for us as website operators, and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Where applicable, Google will transmit this information to third parties if this is prescribed by law, or as long as these third parties process these data on behalf of Google.

If, however, you still wish to prevent the use of Google Analytics, you can install the browser add-on to deactivate Google Analytics. [Get the add-on from Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en "Get the add-on from Google").

As mentioned above, you can prevent the storage of cookies by adjusting your browser software settings accordingly. We would like to inform you, however, that if you do this you may not be able to fully use all the functions on this website.

[More information regarding data usage via Google](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites "More information regarding data usage via Google").

**(bb) Hotjar**

We also use the “Hot Jar” web analysis service from Hotjar Ltd. The information obtained with the assistance of this web analysis service helps us to improve our website and make it more user-friendly. The information that Hotjar captures using cookies includes the navigation through and the interaction with the content on our website. Hotjar also receives information including the IP address (anonymized by abbreviation), screen size and browser information, geographical location (only the respective country), preferred language, referring domain and pages visited (including the page access data and time). 

[Opt out of tracking by Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out "Opt out of tracking by Hotjar").

**(cc) Optimizely**

We use the web analysis service “Optimizely” from Optimizely Inc. for our websites in order to improve functionality, leading to a better user experience. No personal data is transmitted to Optimizely as, per our request, Optimizely anonymizes all IP addresses transmitted by us. 

[More information about how Optimizely Inc. processes data](https://www.optimizely.com/de/privacy/ "More information about how Optimizely Inc. processes data").

You can deactivate this tracking at any time by [following the instructions on the Optimizely website](http://www.optimizely.com/opt_out "following the instructions on the Optimizely website").

**(dd) Webtrekk**

We use the “Webtrekk" tool from Webtrekk GmbH for statistical evaluations of our website. A cookie is used to transmit the relevant information to the Webtrekk tool. The evaluation takes place on an exclusively anonymized basis, in which the last 8 bits of your IP address are deleted and therefore anonymized for subsequent data processing.

The data capture and storage by Webtrekk can be stopped at any time by [clicking this link](https://www.native-instruments.com/en/company/legal-information/privacy-policy/#)

**(ee) Zendesk**

In order to process submitted requests, especially those directed to our customer service team (“Customer Support”), we use the helpdesk system Zendesk. The according functions are supplied by Zendesk, Inc., 989 Market Street #300, San Francisco, CA 94102, USA, who have concluded an order data processing agreement. 

As part of customer support, the following data are saved in Zendesk to enable order processing: Name, email address, telephone number, postal code, city and country. In case of questions regarding the implementation of hardware repairs, complete customer postal addresses are saved in individual cases if this is necessary to process the repairs. 

You can find more information in the [ Zendesk privacy policy](https://www.zendesk.de/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/ " Zendesk privacy policy").

**d) Retargeting**

Retargeting is a variant of online targeting in which users of an online service are marked by suppliers via the retargeting function. This function serves to present visitors to a website with interest-based advertisements as part of the advertising networks. In order to do this, your browser stores cookies which make it possible to recognize you as a visitor when you access websites which belong to the corresponding supplier’s advertising network. These pages display advertisements for products based on your previous internet activity, including products in which you have shown an interest on other websites which use the corresponding provider’s remarketing function.

On our website we mainly use retargeting services from the following suppliers:

**(aa) Criteo**

If you don’t wish to use the Criteo retargeting function, then you can generally deactivate it by [visiting their website](http://www.criteo.com/privacy/ "visiting their website").

**(bb) Facebook**

If you don’t wish to use Facebook’s retargeting function, then you can generally deactivate it [via your Facebook account](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen "via your Facebook account")

**(cc) Google Remarketing**

According to the company’s own information, Google does not capture any personal data during this process. If you don’t wish to use Google’s retargeting function, then you can generally deactivate it by selecting the [according settings](https://adssettings.google.com/ "according settings") on Google.

Alternatively, you can follow these instructions to [deactivate the use of cookies for interest-based advertising](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#! "deactivate the use of cookies for interest-based advertising").

**e) Links to Third-Party Providers**

Links to third-party providers and our internet presence on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube und Soundcloud are embedded in our website. You can activate the redirection by clicking on the relevant symbol (for example the Facebook button) on the lower part of our website. Native Instruments is not responsible for data processing carried out by third-party providers. Please learn more about data processing by reading the relevant company’s privacy notices.

## 3\. Additional Data Processing with Newsletter Subscriptions and Participation in Survey Campaigns, Questionnaires and Competitions

 **a) Newsletter Subscription**

If you wish to receive regular information and news about our services, products and campaigns, you have the option of subscribing to our newsletter on our website by entering your email. 

We use a so-called double-opt-in procedure in our newsletter subscription. This means that after entering your email address you will receive a confirmation email from us, with a request for you to confirm that you wish to receive the newsletter. 

If you have purchased a Native Instrument product or downloaded a so-called “demo” or “free” version of our software, you will also receive a newsletter. Of course, you may withdraw your consent at any time. With the help of this newsletter we will ensure as part of our direct marketing that you will be able to stay up to date with updates, offers and new developments.

The only obligatory information for subscribing and receiving our newsletter is your email address as a technical requirement. 

You can withdraw your consent to receiving the newsletter at any time. In order to do so you can use the following link, which is available in every email.

[withdraw your consent to receiving the newsletter](https://www.native-instruments.com/de/company/newsletter-unsubscribe/ "withdraw your consent to receiving the newsletter").

**b) Survey Campaigns and Questionnaires**

If you have purchased a Native Instruments product, you may receive an email inviting you to participate in a survey. Of course, you may withdraw your consent at any time. With the help of this survey, we would like your feedback in order to continuously improve our products for you. 

**c) Competitions**

At irregular intervals we will invite you to take part in competitions on our website or via newsletter. If you participate, you will be asked to enter your name, surname, email address and country of residence. This information is necessary to allow effective participation in the competition, and is deleted after the competition ends.

## 4\. Contact and Support Service

 **a) Email**

If you contact us via email, we will use your email address and name in order to process your query and contact you if necessary. 

**b) Support Service**

If you use our support service via the helpdesk (only possible for registered users), we will use your email address and name in order to process your query. Additionally, data which you have provided in the entry form regarding your hardware or software are saved and used for resubmission (i.e. if you use further support at a later date) in order to be able to offer you the best possible support in the long term.

## 5\. Additional Data Processing when Setting Up a User Account

In order to be able to see your order data for current and previous orders, as well as the order status of your purchase at any time, you have the option to register a user account on our website.  
The obligatory data we require are your name, email address and your personal password. All other data are voluntary and marked accordingly. 

If you would like to use your user account for product purchases, we require your address and payment information for processing contracts. Obligatory data are marked accordingly. All other data are voluntary.

The personal data submitted relating to this – those which are necessary to fulfil the contract, as well as those which are voluntary – are saved with the option to change or correct them. You can change these data in your customer account in the customer area at any time. 

In order to prevent unauthorized access to your personal data by third parties, in particular your financial data, we secure it according to current technology standards.

## 6\. Product Orders, Product Registration

 **a) Product Orders**

You can place orders in our online shop via your user account by entering the personal data required for order processing.

The captured and saved data required for this purpose and as part of contract processing are: Name, address, email address, payment information. All other data are accordingly marked as voluntary information. 

We will store your order data as part of the order history and send you the order data via email. When confirming your order via email we will not disclose any payment details, only the payment method selected. You can find more information in our [Terms & Conditions.](https://www.native-instruments.com/agb "Terms & Conditions.")

[Access our payment methods](https://www.native-instruments.com/en/shop-information/shipping-fees-payment/ "Access our payment methods").

In compliance with the statutory provisions, your email address, which you entered upon purchasing a payable service, authorizes the use thereof for our own similar products or services. In case of contract conclusion, we will therefore send you advertising for similar products via email from time to time. If you do not wish to receive these advertising emails then you can retract the use of your email address in the newsletter subscription settings.

**b) Product Registration**

Besides the necessary activation of our software products, there is an option to register the purchased hardware via our website within your customer account. When registering the product via the website, the serial number of the respective hardware is stored and assigned to your customer account. 

## 7\. Credit Check and Credit Card Check

For each order which takes place on account or via a credit card, we can check your credit via a credit agency.

## 8\. Sharing Your Personal Information

Native instruments is legally obliged to pass on information to third parties. In particular if there is suspicion of a criminal offence, Native Instruments is obliged to pass the data to law enforcement authorities upon request. This includes the exchange of data with companies which handle credit card fraud. In this regard, there is no sharing of your personal data if the company wishes to use these for commercial use.

Apart from this, we will only use the personal data you entrust us with for processing your products or subscribing to our newsletter. 

For processing newsletter subscriptions, we will pass the email address on to the relevant service provider. This service provider is bound to our instructions as part of an order processing relationship and will not pass your data on to third parties.

In order to process your product orders, we will pass your address data on to a commissioned delivery company and, where applicable, your payment data to banks that we work with. These service providers are also tied to our instructions as part of an order processing relationship and will not pass your data on to third parties.

There is no other transmission of your data to third parties.

## 9\. Right to Information, Deletion and Revocation

 **a) Right to Information**

At all times, you reserve the right to demand information about any of your data which have been stored, as well as its origin, recipients or categories of recipients who have received this data and the purpose of this storage.

**b) Correction**

You retain the right to demand the correction of incorrect personal data. Additionally, considering the purpose of the processing, you retain the right to demand the completion of incomplete personal data.

**c) Deletion**

After ending the respective usage relationship, your personal data are deleted after the statutory tax and trade retention periods, as long as you haven’t expressly – within the framework of your customer account – agreed to the further use of your data.

As long as this does not infringe on statutory retention periods, and as long as your data is no longer required for order processing, you can demand the deletion of your data in compliance with the conditions contained in Art. 17 GDPR.

**d) Right to Limitations on Processing**

You have the right to demand limitations on the processing of your personal data if the conditions according to Art. 18 GDPR are fully met.

**e) Right to Data Portability**

You have the right to receive the personal data concerning you, which you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format, as well as the data of other responsible persons without hinderance by Native Instruments, as long as the requirements of Art. 20 GDPR are fully met.

**f) Right of Objection**

In accordance with Art. 21 GDPR, you have the right of appeal due to reasons which result from a special situation, against the processing of the personal data concerning your person, which arise due to Art. 6 Abs. 1 e) or f) GDPR.

**g) Revocation**

If you have given approval for the use of your data, you can revoke it without form at any time, effective for the future, which may result in you no longer being able to use our services in their entirety. 

**h) Right of Appeal**

Irrespective of other administrative or legal recourse, you retain the right of appeal to a regulatory authority, in particular in the member state where you are residing, your place of work, or the location of the alleged infringement, if you believe that our processing of your personal data is in violation of data protection laws.

**i) Contact Information**

For revocation as well as requests for information or deletion, please contact:

Native Instruments GmbH  
Data protection officer: Kai-Hendrik Weutzing  
Email: privacy@native-instruments.de
